milletsports.co.uk 2015-12-06

# Privacy and Security | Millet Sports

## About Us

Millet Sports is part of the [ _JD Sports Fashion Group_](http://www.milletsports.co.uk/about/history/group-brands) and, for the purposes of the information which you provide to us, acts as the data controller. This means that we are responsible for what happens to the information that you give to us. We will at all times compile with the Data Protection Act 1998 and make sure that we keep your data secure and steps are taken to prevent any unauthorised access to your information. From time to time, we will share the information which you provide to us with other group companies within the [JD Sports Fashion Group](http://www.milletsports.co.uk/about/history/group-brands). _  
_

[_JD Sports Fashion Group_](http://www.milletsports.co.uk/about/history/group-brands) is constantly growing and changing. We will always update the web page here, so you should take a look from time to time to see if new companies have joined the group or if any company leaves our group. 

## The Millet Sports' Privacy Policy

We take the safety and security of your details seriously at Millet Sports, which is why whenever we collect any details from you we will always use a secure encrypted form to do so. When you submit your details to us they are encrypted into a secure code that only we have the key to decipher.

We keep all of your personal information on a secure server and treat all information you provide us with as confidential. For added security, we do not keep any card payment details on our database. Instead, we use a secure payment gateway to verify all transactions and guard against fraud, which only passes a secure code to us that does not contain any sensitive data once it has approved the transaction.

We only use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * Processing your order(s)

  * Administering your account (if you have one)

  * Communicating the status of your order to you

  * To administer this website

  * To serve website content to you

  * To notify you of special offers, products and services that you may be interested in provided you have consented for us to do so

  * To run any competitions that you have entered

  * To administer any promotional offers or discounts that you are entitled to

We may contact you using any of the information you have provided us, such as by email or telephone for the above purposes. If you have opted in to receive marketing communications you are able to unsubscribe at anytime just by letting us know via email to enquiries@milletsports.co.uk. The information collected about you will not be used for any other purposes and will not be sold or otherwise disclosed to any other organisations, except to (i) other companies within our group, (ii) our or their successors in title and (iii) third party service providers engaged by us (or other members of our group) to help operate our business effectively. 

From time to time your personal information may be processed by systems which are located outside the United Kingdom. Where this happens, we will ensure that your information will be kept secure and your privacy rights remain protected consistent with the Data Protection Act 1998.

We also use your data for marketing purposes which may mean that you will receive marketing communications from us, other companies within the [_JD Sports Fashion Group_](http://www.milletsports.co.uk/about/history/group-brands) or carefully selected third parties. However if you do receive marketing communications from other companies, we will endeavour to ensure that the company in question and it's products will be as relevant to you as possible.

To help make ordering with Millet Sports easier, we may send emails relating to orders that have not been completed. You can opt out from these using the usual methods or by following the instructions in the emails.

We may also collect data (user information) on your browsing habits whilst on our site (such as the URL or advert you came from, the geographical area of your computer, the pages you browsed and the search terms you entered whilst on our Website). This is common when shopping online and allows us to improve our Website, your user experience and our quality of service. We will collect this information as a matter of course for all users who access our Website whether they are registered with us or not.

We may disclose your personal information to reputable third parties (such as payment processing companies or couriers) who help to process and fulfil your order. We require that these companies treat your personal information as confidential and comply fully with current UK consumer and Data Protection legislation. Aside from this, we will not pass on your personal information to any third parties unless you give us your permission to do so.

If the police or any other regulatory or government authority requests your personal or user information in relation to an investigation into suspected illegal activities, then we may be obliged to provide it to them.

We may update our Privacy policy from time to time so please check back frequently to ensure you are aware of any changes. Any questions regarding our Privacy policy or if you would like to obtain details of the personal information we hold on you, then please write to the address below. Please note that there is currently a statutory fee of £10 that we will charge if you wish to access your information.

Data Controller

ActivInstinct

4 Hertsmere Industrial Park  
Warwick Road,  
Borehamwood,  
Herts  
WD6 1GT

You can also contact us by telephone on 020 8732 7340 or via email to [enquiries@milletsports.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@milletsports.co.uk)

Like most shopping sites, we use cookies to keep track of your current session on our Website and to enable you store items in your shopping basket whilst you are on the site. A cookie is a small text file that a website sends to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Most browsers are set to accept cookies by default, but you do not have to accept cookies and your browser will give you the option of whether to accept or reject them.

We use cookies to store items in your basket and so if your browser is set to reject cookies you will be unable to shop on our Website, however you will still be able to browse our product and information pages.

Cookies are completely safe and do not store any personal information, but allow us to understand when you visit our Website, how you use it and what products and services you might be interested in. This enables us to personalise the content you see on the Website so that we show you things that are most relevant to you and also to test changes to the Website to improve your online experience. For more information on cookies, you can visit the Information Commissioner's Office website www.ico.gov.uk

We are constantly working to improve our Website and the experience that our customers have when they visit it and we work with trusted partners who use cookies to enable us to show you products or services that we think may be relevant to you based on previous purchases or browsing behaviour. If you leave our Website to visit certain selected third party websites we can also provide adverts and offers related to products that you have recently viewed or might be interested in. To do this, we work with partners who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and for more information on this or to opt out of seeing our ads on third party sites [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

If cookies are not enabled on your computer then you will not be able to shop on our site as we use them to record what products you place in your shopping basket. By using our site, you consent to cookies being used as we set out here.

## Managing Cookies

To check whether you have cookies enabled on your computer, and easy way of doing this is adding a product to your shopping basket and if you are taken to the basket and the product you added is there then you already have cookies enabled.

If you want to check in your browser’s actual settings, then this will vary depending on the type of browser you have. If you have a PC then click help on the menu bar at the top of your browser (if you can’t see this then press the alt key once and it should display), and select the ‘about’ option. If you have a Mac, whilst you are in the browser window, click on the Apple menu and select the ‘about’ option.

## Checking if cookies are enabled

**For PC browsers**

**Microsoft Internet Explorer:**

Click on the ‘tools’ button at the top right of your browser (it looks like a cog) and choose ‘Internet options’. Once this opens, click on the ‘Privacy’ tab and set the privacy level to medium, which is the recommended setting and will allow cookies.   A setting higher than medium will disable cookies and you will be unable to shop on our site.

**Google Chrome:**

Click on the ‘tools’ button at the top right of your browser (it looks like a spanner) and choose ‘settings’. Once this opens, click on show advanced settings, scroll to the privacy section and click on ‘Content settings’. Once here, select ‘Allow local data to be set’ (this is Google’s recommended setting). If other settings are selected then you will be unable to shop on our site.

**Mozilla Firefox:**

Click on ‘Tools’ at the top of your browser (you may have to press the alt key to display this) and select ‘Options’. Once this opens, select ‘Privacy’ and make sure that the ‘Tracking’ checkbox marked ‘Tell websites I do not want to be tracked’ is left unchecked.   If this is checked then you will be unable to shop on our site.

**Safari:**

Click on the ‘settings’ button at the top right of your browser (it looks like a cog) and select the ‘Preferences’ option. Once this opens, select ‘Privacy’ and for the ‘Block cookies’ option, select ‘never’. Blocking cookies will mean that you are unable to shop on our site.

**For Mac browsers**

**Microsoft Internet Explorer:**

Click on 'Explorer' at the top of your browser and select the 'Preferences' option. Once this opens, scroll to ‘Cookies’ under ‘Receiving Files’ and select the ‘Never Ask’ option. If another option is selected then you will be unable to shop on our site.

**Safari:**

Click the ‘Safari’ button at the top of your browser and select the ‘Preferences’ option. Once this opens, select ‘Privacy’ and for the ‘Block cookies’ option, select ‘never’. Blocking cookies will mean that you are unable to shop on our site

**Mozilla Firefox:**

Click the ‘Firefox’ button at the top of your browser and select ‘Privacy’, then select ‘Firefox will’ and select ‘Use custom settings for history’. Check ‘Accept cookies from sites and ‘Accept third-party cookies’ and select ‘Keep until they expire’ and click ‘OK’. If you do not select to accept cookies, you will be unable to shop on our site.

**Opera:**

Click on 'Menu' at the top of your browser and select 'Settings', then 'Preferences'. Once this opens, select the 'Advanced' tab and select the 'Accept cookies' option. If this option is not set to accept cookies then you will be unable to shop on our site.

## Cookies we use

Cookie | Purpose  
---|---  
basket | This cookie keeps track of items selected and place in the basket and allows the checkout process to function.  
profile | This cookie enables us to serve relevant products and offers to customers based on browsing behaviour.  
userregion | This cookie enables us to display content that is relevant to your country (including pricing and delivery options).  
mobileondesktopsite  
mobile  
desktop | These cookies enable us to display and determine the correct version of our website to a user such as the desktop version - or a version tailored to mobile devices.  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmz | These cookies are placed by Google Analytics, which we use to record anonymous statistics about the usage of our site.  
mmcore.mmact  
mmcore.pd  
mmcore.srv  
mmcore.tst  
mmid  
mmpa.tst | These cookies are placed by Maxymiser, which we use to carry out tests for new website functionality and to serve product recommendations to customers.
